Emilio Quiambao

Creative Technologist

San Francisco, CA

emilioq.github.io

emilioquiambao@gmail.com (650) 296-3335

Projects

Environmental Hazard Website

Developed an environmental hazard website from scratch with a team of seven students. Worked as full stack developer and back-end lead. Created vertical prototype with Django framework and MySQL Workbench on AWS Server. Documented project milestones.

Data Wrangler Management Project

A real world I.T. project management case of a data wrangling software. Created the business case, project infrastructure, scope management plan, work breakdown structure, schedule, and budget.

Webcam Music

An app created in a 24-hour hackathon using Processing. Webcam is used to create music based on pictures taken.

Particle Life

Inspired by Conway's Game of Life, a javascript app utilizing particles to simulate organic movement.

Android Event Browser

Android app developed using Android Studio. Implements Meetup and Volley API. Able to search and display info retrieved from Meetup API in a card list.

ASCII Maze Solver

Receives an ASCII maze file and displays it correspondingly in graphics. A solution is then generated and a character sprite follows the path.

Work Experience

CasaOne

Operations Associate

Sep 2019 - Present | Emeryville, CA

- » Managed all aspects of day-to-day operations.
- » Lead projects to improve or implement services.
- » Worked closely with engineering/product team to improve the administrative system's design.

The X Kids

Technology Camp School Instructor Feb 2017 – Aug 2017 | San Francisco, CA

- » Taught kids robotics, coding, and chess.
- » Ages range from kindergarten to middle school.

Skills

Software Engineering Process

Knowledge of full SE lifecycle including common and best practices for SE teamwork and SE processes.

Business Operations

Experienced in I.T. Project Management. Knowledgeable of the project life cycle, systems development life cycle, and project management body of knowledge areas.

Programming
Languages
Ableton Live
FL Studio
JavaScript
Python
HTML & CSS
Ableton Live
FL Studio
rekordbox
Traktor
Sony Vegas

C, C++ Adobe CC
SQL Processing / p5.js
Lua TouchDesigner
PHP OBS Studio

Software Tools

Django S Bootstrap A Git. GitHub U

MySQL Workbench

VirtualBox Android Studio

Project Management

Slack

Agile/Scrum

User-centered design Skype, Zoom

Trello

Education

San Francisco State University

BS in Computer Science | Aug 2014 - Dec 2018 GPA: 3.59

University of Seoul

BS in Computer Science | Aug 2017 - Jan 2018

Activities

Association for Computer Machinery

Organization where engineer and CS students share projects, ideas, and tech news.

International Education Exchange Council

Student organization encouraging international education, student exchange and sharing of cultures between international and domestic students.

SF State Exchange Program

Studied abroad in Seoul, Korea for a semester with GKS scholarship. Studied artifical intelligence.